AMELIA VICTORIA MARKHAM

112 Plimsoll Road, Highbury, London, N4 2ED

Mobile: 07914 318782

E-Mail: ameliavmarkham@gmail.com

Personal Profile

Bringing together my background as a planner at a media agency and as a strategist at a creative consultancy, I have a close understanding of specific media channels, including digital and social, and strong knowledge of audience profiling and data analysis, as well as a higher level understanding of creative effectiveness and strategic frameworks. With this breadth of experience I am now looking – and feel I am well positioned – for a new challenge within planning and strategy.

Work Experience

Feb. 2020 — Strategist Contagious (London)

- Play a leading role in projects to embed creative excellence at clients such as AB InBev and Pernod Ricard by delivering training modules, developing workshops, and producing content on creative effectiveness and the briefing and evaluation process
- Support on broader strategic projects, such as helping Unilever to develop and launch its purpose-led marketing philosophy
- Work on an ad-hoc basic producing in-depth insight reports and presentations on topics within marketing, consumer culture and technology, for clients such as Google, Disney and LEGO, to help guide creative thinking and communications strategies
- Present at company events on the latest trends in creativity and culture, including online webinars, workshops, and the annual conference, Most Contagious
- Regularly contribute thought pieces and articles to the company's subscription platform, blog, and quarterly magazine

Sep. 2015 – Feb. 2020 Planner/Buyer the7stars (London)

- Acted as the main agency contact across clients including Deliveroo, PizzaExpress, MADE.com, Capital One, Vanguard, and Save the Children
- Collaborated closely with a team of specialists to develop cross-channel media campaigns in response to briefs with budgets of up to £50m
- Used industry tools to interrogate audience behaviour, analyse data, and conduct competitive reviews with the aim to uncover insights to inform communications
- Worked alongside the strategy team to develop longer-term media strategies and communications platforms
- Bought media across offline channels including cinema, radio, press, OOH and direct mail, worked closely with media partners to develop and deliver partnerships, and led negotiations with sales teams to deliver the best value for clients
- Participated in pitches, including leading on the development of a framework and presenting to prospective clients during a pitch that brought in £15m of new business to the agency
- Contributed to the wider agency by managing the company's PR output, acting as editor of a monthly publication sent to all clients featuring thought pieces and providing insight on industry trends, and running the agency's social media channels

Internships

Aug. 2015

Public Relations Assistant Quite Great PR (Cambridge)

 Assisted in the company's music promotion services, including drafting press releases, organising features to be published online, and compiling reports to send to clients

Aug. 2013 – Feb. 2014 Public Relations Officer

William & Mary Global Film Festival (Williamsburg, USA)

 Curated the festival programme and organised events. As part of the PR team, prepared press releases, contacted regional media outlets, and copy edited website content

Jun. 2011 Researcher

Landmark Europe, Public Affairs Agency (Brussels, Belgium)

 Analysed data and prepared client briefings to aid the development of communications strategies

Education and Qualifications

2011 - 2015

University of St Andrews

MA (Hons) Film Studies and Psychology, First-Class Honours

- Attained the Richard Dyer Award for the Top Performing Film Studies Graduate and the Anita Loos Award for Most Outstanding Undergraduate Essay in Film Studies (2015)
- Selected for a competitive programme to study abroad at the College of William & Mary, USA (2013-2014)
- Extra-curricular activities included: The Stand (student publication), St Andrews Student Radio, On the Rocks Arts Festival, and St Andrews Green Film Festival

2006 - 2011

Stamford High School, Stamford, Lincs

- A-Levels: Psychology (A*), English (A), and German (A); AS-Levels: Geography (A)
- GCSEs: 12 (8A*, 4A), including Maths, English, French and German

Qualifications & Skills

- IPA Foundation Certificate (Distinction), IPA Fundamentals of Branding, IPA LegRegs, IPA Commercial Certificate, and Accredited MIPA
- Strong knowledge of research tools including Mintel, WARC, GWI, Mediatel, Kantar, TGI/ Telmar, Touchpoints, Brandwatch, Google Analytics, YouGov Profiles & BrandIndex, and Nielsen AdDynamix; basic knowledge of Adobe Suite

Hobbies & Interests

 Following and attending football matches, playing and watching cricket, yoga, pub quizzes, reading (particularly fiction, social psychology, and urban planning and transport), travelling